We have talked about how vectorization
我们已经讨论过向量化
lets you speed up your code significantly.
是如何显著地加速你的代码
In this video, we'll talk about how you can vectorize
在这次视频中，我们将会谈及向量化是如何
the implementation of logistic regression,
实现在逻辑回归的上面的
so they can process an entire training set,
这样就能在处理整个训练集时
that is implement a single elevation of
gradient descent with respect to an entire training set
来实现梯度下降算法的单方面优化
without using even a single explicit for loop.
而且甚至用不到一个明确的for循环
I'm super excited about this technique,
对于这一项技术 我特别兴奋
and when we talk about neural networks later without
并且当我们后面谈及神经网络时
using even a single explicit for loop.
同样也用不到一个明确的for循环
Let's get started. Let's first examine
那我们开始吧 我们先回顾
the forward propagation steps of logistic regression.
逻辑回归的正向传播步骤
So, if you have m training examples,
所以，若果你有m个训练样本
then to make a prediction on the first example,
那么对第一个样本进行预测
you need to compute that,
你需要这样计算
compute z. I'm using this familiar formula,
计算出z 运用这个熟悉的公式
then compute the activations,
然后计算激活函数
you compute y hat in the first example.
计算在第一个样本的y冒（预测值）
Then to make a prediction on the second training example,
然后继续去对第二个训练样本做一个预测
you need to compute that.
你需要这样计算
Then, to make a prediction on the third example,
然后去对第三个样本做一个预测
you need to compute that, and so on.
你需要这样计算 以此类推
And you might need to do this m times,
你可能需要这样做上m次
if you have M training examples.
如果你有m个样本
So, it turns out, that in order to
可以看出 为了
carry out the forward propagation step,
执行正向传播步骤
that is to compute these predictions on our m training examples,
需要对m个训练样本都计算出预测结果
there is a way to do so,
但有一个办法可以
without needing an explicit for loop.
不需要任何一个明确的for循环
Let's see how you can do it.
让我们看看如何做到
First, remember that we defined a matrix capital X to be your training inputs,
首先，记得我们曾定义过一个矩阵大写X来作为你的训练输入
stacked together in different columns like this.
像这样子在不同的列中堆积在一起
So, this is a matrix,
这就是一个矩阵
that is a NX by M matrix.
这是一个N_x行m列的矩阵
So, I'm writing this as a Python numpy shape,
我现在写的是Python numpy形式
this just means that X is a NX by m dimensional matrix.
这只是意味X是一个N_x乘以m维的矩阵
Now, the first thing I want to do is show how you can compute Z1, Z2,
现在我首先想要做的是告诉你如何计算z1 z2
Z3 and so on,
以及z3 等等
all in one step,
全都在一个步骤中
in fact, with one line of code.
事实上，仅用了一行代码
So, I'm going to construct a 1
所以我要先构建一个 1×m 的矩阵
by M matrix that's really a row vector while I'm going to compute Z1,
实际上就是一个行向量  然后当我计算z1
Z2, and so on,
z2 等等
down to ZM, all at the same time.
一直到zm 都是在同一时间内（完成计算）
It turns out that this can be expressed as
结果发现它可以表达成
W transpose to capital matrix X plus and then this vector B,
W的转置乘以大写矩阵X加上这个向量b
B and so on.
b,等等
B, where this thing,
b 这个东西
this B, B, B, B,
这个 b b b b
B thing is a 1xM vector or
这个东西就是一个1×m的向量 或者
1xM matrix or that is as a M dimensional row vector.
1×m 的矩阵 或者说是一个m维的行向量
So hopefully there you are with matrix multiplication.
希望你比较熟悉矩阵乘法
You might see that W transpose X1,
那么就会发现 W转置（乘上）x1
X2 and so on to XM,
x2 等等 一直到xm
that W transpose can be a row vector.
这个W转置可以是一个行向量
So this W transpose will be a row vector like that.
所以W转置会是一个这样的行向量
And so this first term will evaluate to W transpose X1,
所以第一个项的关于W转置乘X1
W transpose X2 and so on, dot, dot, dot,
W转置乘X2 等等 点点点
W transpose XM, and then we add this second term B,
W转置乘xm 然后我们加上第二项b
B, B, and so on,
b b 等等
you end up adding B to each element.
当你给每个元素加上b后就结束了
So you end up with another 1xM vector.
所以结束后得出一个1×m的向量
Well that's the first element,
这是第一个元素
that's the second element and so on,
这是第二个元素等等
and that's the nth element.
这是第n个元素
And if you refer to the definitions above,
如果你参考上面的定义
this first element is exactly the definition of Z1.
第一个元素恰恰是z1的定义
The second element is exactly the definition of Z2 and so on.
第二个元素恰恰是z2的定义 等等
So just as X was once obtained,
所以X是一次性获得的
when you took your training examples and
当你把你的训练样本都堆积在一起
stacked them next to each other, stacked them horizontally.
一个挨着一个 横向堆积
I'm going to define capital Z to be this where
我将会把大写Z定义为这个 在这里
you take the lowercase Z's and stack them horizontally.
你用小写z表示 横向排在一起
So when you stack the lower case X's corresponding to
所以当你将对应于不同训练样本
a different training examples,horizontally
的小写x们横向的堆积起来时
you get this variable capital X and
你得到了这个变量 大写X
the same way when you take these lowercase Z variables,
小写z变量也是同样的处理
and stack them horizontally,
把他们横向地堆积起来
you get this variable capital Z.
你就得到了这个变量 大写Z
And it turns out, that in order to implement this,
结果发现 为了计算这个
the numpy command is capital Z equals NP dot w dot T,
numpy的指令为大写Z = np.dot(w.T)
that's w transpose X and then plus b.
(这是w的转置) Z = np.dot(w.T,X) + b
Now there is a subtlety in Python,
这里有个Python巧妙的地方
which is at here b is a real number
在这个地方b是一个实数
or if you want to say you know 1x1 matrix,
或者你可以说是1×1的矩阵
is just a normal real number.
就是一个普通的实数
But, when you add this vector to this real number,
但是 当你把向量加上这个实数时
Python automatically takes this real number B
Python会自动的把实数b
and expands it out to this 1XM row vector.
扩展成一个1×m的行向量
So in case this operation seems a little bit mysterious,
所以这个操作看上去有一点神秘
this is called broadcasting in Python,
在Python中这叫做广播(broadcasting)
and you don't have to worry about it for now,
目前你不用对此感到顾虑
we'll talk about it some more in the next video.
我们会在下一节视频中更多的谈及它
But the takeaway is that with just one line of code, with this line of code,
再说回来 只要用一行的代码 运用这行代码
you can calculate capital Z
你可以计算大写Z
and capital Z is going to be a 1XM matrix
而大写Z是一个1×m的矩阵
that contains all of the lower cases Z's.
包含所有的小写z们
Lowercase Z1 through lower case ZM.
小写z1一直到小写zm
So that was Z, how about these values a.
这就是Z（的内容） 那么变量a是怎样的呢
What we like to do next,
我们接下去要做的
is find a way to compute A1,
是找到一个办法来计算a1
A2 and so on to AM,
a2等等一直到am
all at the same time,
都在同一时间完成
and just as stacking lowercase X's resulted in
就像把小写x们堆积起来形成
capital X and stacking horizontally lowercase Z's resulted in capital Z,
大写X 还有横向的堆积小写z们形成大写Z
stacking lower case A,
堆积小写a
is going to result in a new variable,
就会形成一个新的变量
which we are going to define as capital A.
我们把它定义为大写A
And in the program assignment,
在编程作业中
you see how to implement a vector valued sigmoid function,
你能看到如何对一个向量进行sigmoid函数操作
so that the sigmoid function,
所以sigmoid函数
inputs this capital Z as a variable and very efficiently outputs capital A.
把大写Z当做一个变量进行输入 然后非常高效的输出大写A
So you see the details of that in the programming assignment.
你仔细看看编程作业里的细节
So just to recap,
总的来说
what we've seen on this slide is that instead of needing to loop over
我们在这张幻灯片所看到的是 不需要for循环
M training examples to compute lowercase Z and lowercase A,
（就可以）从m个训练样本来一次性计算出小写z和小写a
one of the time, you can implement this one line of code,
而你运行这些只需要一行代码
to compute all these Z's at the same time.
在同一时间计算所有的z
And then, this one line of code,
这一行的代码
with appropriate implementation of
通过恰当地一次性运用
lowercase Sigma to compute all the lowercase A's all at the same time.
小写的sigma来计算所有的小写a们
So this is how you implement
所以这就是你如何执行
a vectorize implementation of
一个向量的操作
the forward propagation for all M training examples at the same time.
来对所有的m个训练样本 在同一时间计算它的正向传播
So to summarize, you've just seen how you can use
概括一下 你刚刚看到如何
vectorization to very efficiently compute all of the activations,
使用向量化得以高效的计算激活函数
all the lowercase A's at the same time.
在同一时间算出小写a们
Next, it turns out, you can also use vectorization very
接下来 你会发现同样可以用向量化来
efficiently to compute the backward propagation,
高效地计算反向传播
to compute the gradients.
并以此来计算梯度
Let's see how you can do that, in the next video.
我们在下一次视频中 将看到它如何实现